<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on Port 8080 by Chakri</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on Port 8080 by Chakri</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:11:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Third post</title><link>/posts/third-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/third-post/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;testsetests&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deep in the Workshop</title><link>/posts/second-adventure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/second-adventure/</guid><description>Spent the afternoon taking apart an old mechanism. There is something meditative about understanding how things click together — and the quiet satisfaction when they do again.</description></item><item><title>First Adventure</title><link>/posts/first-adventure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/first-adventure/</guid><description>Kicked off the first entry — a rough-around-the-edges start, but every good log has to begin somewhere. The CMS is live and the words are flowing.</description></item><item><title>Building My Homelab from Scratch</title><link>/posts/homelab-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/homelab-setup/</guid><description>Started with a spare ThinkPad and a dream. Six months later I am running 14 containers, a reverse proxy, and a UPS that has already saved me twice. Here is the full parts list and what I would do differently.</description></item><item><title>Docker Compose Patterns I Keep Coming Back To</title><link>/posts/docker-compose-patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/docker-compose-patterns/</guid><description>After writing hundreds of compose files, a handful of patterns have become muscle memory — named volumes over bind mounts for databases, always pinning image tags, and the restart policy nobody puts in their first file.</description></item><item><title>Reverse Proxy 101: Caddy vs Nginx vs Traefik</title><link>/posts/reverse-proxy-101/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/reverse-proxy-101/</guid><description>Ran all three in production over the past year. Caddy wins on simplicity and auto-HTTPS, Traefik wins for dynamic Docker routing, and Nginx wins when you need to search the error and actually find an answer.</description></item><item><title>My Monitoring Stack: Prometheus, Grafana, and Sanity</title><link>/posts/monitoring-stack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/monitoring-stack/</guid><description>Setting up Prometheus and Grafana felt like overkill for a homelab until the day my NAS ran out of disk at 3am and I did not know until morning. Now every service I run has a dashboard. Sleep quality improved.</description></item><item><title>Self-Hosting Gitea: Two Years In</title><link>/posts/git-server-self-hosted/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/git-server-self-hosted/</guid><description>Two years of running my own Gitea instance instead of pushing everything to GitHub. The migration took an afternoon. The maintenance is basically zero. And having a private mirror of every repo I care about is the kind of peace of mind that&amp;rsquo;s hard to put a price on.</description></item></channel></rss>